Morris Florek

github.com/morrisfl

➤ morris.florek@gmx.de

in www.linkedin.com/in/morris-florek \$\mathcal{J}\$ +49 152 53488837



Master's graduate in the program Digital Engineering, a program which provided me with a unique mix of engineering and computer science. Proven experiments in the field of deep learning for computer vision as a research assistant, through my thesis and a research project. Delivered results in image retrieval, object detection, image classification and dataset curation.

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, Java, MATLAB, C++
- Programming Frameworks: PyTorch, MMDetection, OpenCV, Jupyter, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib
- Tools: Git/GitHub, Anaconda, IntelliJ PyCharm
- Technologies: Deep Learning, Computer Vision
- Languages: German (Native), English (C1), French (B1)

EXPERIENCE

Bauhaus-University Weimar

Weimar, Germany

Research Assistant - Chair of Computer Vision

04/2023 - 12/2023

- o Responsibility: Tutor in the course Deep Learning for Computer Vision. Responsible for presenting exercises and sample solutions, as well as guiding the final projects.
- o Accomplishments: Advanced use of Python and PyTorch to train and evaluate deep neural networks for image classification and object detection.

RiB Software GmbH

Working Student - iECO Research Project

Leipzig, Germany 04/2022 - 03/2023

DB Engineering & Consulting

Working Student - Structural Engineering Planning Department

Stuttgart, Germany 04/2021 - 03/2022

Köster GmbH

Working Student - Construction Management

Stuttgart, Germany 01/2019 - 03/2021

EDUCATION

Bauhaus-University Weimar

M.Sc. Digital Engineering

Weimar, Germany 10/2021 - 04/2024

- o Thesis: Efficient and Discriminative Image Feature Extraction for Multi-Domain Image Retrieval
- o Relevant Courses: Photogrammetric Computer Vision, Image analysis and object recognition, Introduction to Natural Language Processing, Software Engineering, Algorithms and Data Structures, Object-oriented Modeling and Programming in Engineering
- o Final Grade: 1.4 (German grade) / 3.6 (US GPA)

University of Stuttgart

Stuttgart, Germany 10/2016 - 07/2021

B.Sc. Civil Engineering

- Thesis: The behavior of structural steel after thermal exposure
- Relevant Courses: Higher Mathematics 1/2/3, Statistics & Computer Science
- o Final Grade: 2.2 (German grade) / 2.8 (US GPA)

Projects

- Universal Feature Extraction: Fine-tuning of different foundation models (CLIP, DINOv2, SAM, ...) on a custom curated training dataset for the task of universal image retrieval. A Kaggle challenge was used to evaluate and compare the models against other approaches.
- Dataset Refinement: Enhance the class granularity of the Stanford Cars dataset by fine-tuning a car color classification model to classify the cars not only by model but also by color.
- RODSL: Robust Object Detection with Soft-Label, a research project about exploring different methods (majority voting, weighted boxes fusion, expectation-maximization) to extract ground truth from multi-annotated images. The methods were evaluated by training and evaluating object detection and instance segmentation models using the MMDetection framework.

PUBLICATIONS

• Drawing the Same Bounding Box Twice? Coping Noisy Annotations in Object Detection with Repeated Labels: Tschirschwitz, D., Benz, C., Florek, M., Noerderhus, H., Stein, B., & Rodehorst, V., In: Proceedings of the DAGM German Conference on Pattern Recognition (GCPR), 2023.